Guide to the John Patrick Hawker papers, 1942-2009
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
- John Patrick Hawker papers, 1940s-2008
  - Notes on radio equipment and colleagues, 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Further war related notes, hand trimmed and pasted into 3 small cardstock booklets, autobiographical and instructional in nature (for field radio agents}, also containing names of colleagues and types of radio equipment.
  - Personal wartime recollections on SCU9, MI5 and MI6, and other descriptions of clandestine events in Europe, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 17-18)
    Two folders featuring Hawker's personal wartime accounts Including an autobiographical sketch which includes his important service with SCU9, a description of his arrival in Paris, an insider's perspective of the Ml6 and MI5, further filled with manuscript notes on Russian Clandestine Radio, a calendar of events relating to Czechoslovakia from 1939 to 1942, exposes on sabotages and secret Allied-German collaboration, resistance in Holland, and a timeline history of the Government Code and Cipher School (GC&CS}.
  - Photocopied research material on German and Russian radio technology, 1980s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 19-22)
    A substantial collection of copied printed material on the German two-way radio system, replete with diagrams and illustration, featuring a German manual for equipment used by their military intelligence division, titled "Funkgerate des Militarischen Nachrichtendienstes " and an account on short waves titled "Die Funkpeilung der Kurzen Wellen." Also with information in German dealing with the R-350 and R-350M Russian spy radio sets developed in the former USS R in the mid 1950s, this lot of papers facilitates a technical study of various instruments such as suitcase radios. their mechanical design, specific components, application and efficiency. Together with a letter from a friend enquiring about Eastern Bloc B2 spyset radios.